[SPEAKER_00]: Chair now recognizes Miss Marjorie Taylor-Green from Georgia.
[SPEAKER_01]: Thank you, Mr. Chairman.
[SPEAKER_01]: Miss Cheadle, I'd like to remind you that you're under oath.
[SPEAKER_01]: The site team has a senior supervisor, an advanced team, a protective intelligence team, a counter sniper element, and detail.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who was the agent in charge?
[SPEAKER_01]: How long has she been the agent in charge?
[SPEAKER_01]: And what is her Secret Service background?
[SPEAKER_02]: So I'm not going to provide a name.
[SPEAKER_01]: Why not?
[SPEAKER_01]: You're here to answer our questions for him.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'm not going to provide names of you stated in your testimony.
[SPEAKER_01]: You said I am here today to answer your questions.
[SPEAKER_02]: That is correct.
[SPEAKER_01]: Answer the question.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'm not going to provide names of our personnel.
[SPEAKER_01]: Why not?
[SPEAKER_01]: The American people are demanding these answers from you today, Ms.
[SPEAKER_01]: Cheadle.
[SPEAKER_02]: I will do the best to provide you accurate information based on the facts that I have at this time.
[SPEAKER_01]: You're not answering our questions.
[SPEAKER_01]: The advance element coordinates with other Intel or law enforcement partners, identifies threats and weaknesses at the sites and movements.
[SPEAKER_01]: We'd like a copy of the advance report.
[SPEAKER_01]: Have you brought it here with you today?
[SPEAKER_02]: We will comply with the request for the documentation that has been requested.
[SPEAKER_01]: When will that be, Ms.
[SPEAKER_01]: Cheadle, because you should have brought it today.
[SPEAKER_02]: I am certain that our personnel are working on obtaining all of that document.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't believe you, and neither do the people watching this hearing.
[SPEAKER_01]: You're not doing well, as Mr. Moskowitz informed you.
[SPEAKER_01]: You have been sitting here for over three hours and I have you know the entire country is demanding you resign and demanding that you be fired if you do not resign.
[SPEAKER_01]: Things are not going well for you.
[SPEAKER_01]: You need to answer the questions.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was there a protective intelligence team and what technical resources were utilized for that event, specifically drone or helicopter assets?
[SPEAKER_02]: There were a number of technical assets that were deployed for that event, and there was a protective intelligence team that was assigned to that event.
[SPEAKER_01]: Why was Crooks able to fly a drone over the entire area the day of the rally and the day of his assassination attempt?
[SPEAKER_02]: To my knowledge, he did not fly the drone over the entire area.
[SPEAKER_01]: How did he fly a drone over the area, period?
[SPEAKER_01]: Any part of the area?
[SPEAKER_02]: Again, I would have to go back and check the timeline of when that took place and when the...
[SPEAKER_01]: Why didn't you bring the timeline with you today to answer our questions?
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't have all of the answers on the timelines based on the criminal investigation.
[SPEAKER_01]: Were you not prepared today to answer our questions?
[SPEAKER_02]: I am prepared to answer the questions based on the information and wanted to be able to provide...
[SPEAKER_01]:
Do you have a timeline that you... Do you have a timeline, at all, from any of the day?
[SPEAKER_02]: I have a timeline that does not have specifics.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's shocking.
[SPEAKER_01]: That is absolutely unacceptable.
[SPEAKER_01]: That means you are a failure at your job.
[SPEAKER_01]: Let's talk about things that are prohibited in Trump rallies.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I've been to a lot of Trump rallies.
[SPEAKER_01]: Backpacks and bags.
[SPEAKER_01]: Bicycles.
[SPEAKER_01]: Firearms.
[SPEAKER_01]: any type of weapon or any other item determined to be a potential safety hazard, like a range finder would be one.
[SPEAKER_01]: At 5:10, Crooks is first observed by one of the snipers, ATR Sniper One, at the building.
[SPEAKER_01]: 5:10, President Trump was shot in the face at 6-11 p.m.
[SPEAKER_01]: 5:28, ATR Sniper One takes a picture of a bicycle in two bags.
[SPEAKER_01]: Those belong to Crooks.
[SPEAKER_01]: 5:32, AGR Sniper One spots Crooks looking at his phone and using a range finder.
[SPEAKER_01]: 5:55, Butler ESU Command confirms receipt of photos and states they have been relayed on.
[SPEAKER_01]: 6:05 PM, AGR Sniper One later communicates that Crooks is seen moving northeast in direction of Sheets and that Crooks has a backpack.
[SPEAKER_01]: Two minutes before the shooting, while President Trump has been allowed to take the stage, people see Crooks laying on his stomach in a sniper position on the roof, and they're yelling he has a gun, and they are trying to alert law enforcement and Secret Service.
[SPEAKER_01]: Why was Crooks not shot by the snipers?
[SPEAKER_01]: Why was he allowed to be there?
[SPEAKER_02]: As soon as the individual was identified as a threat, they were...
[SPEAKER_01]: No, no, no, no, no, no. What do you consider to be a threat?
[SPEAKER_01]: A man with a gun laying in a sniper position?
[SPEAKER_01]: A man that had a backpack?
[SPEAKER_01]: A man that had a bicycle?
[SPEAKER_01]: A man that had a range finder?
[SPEAKER_01]: At what point is he determined a threat?
[SPEAKER_02]: An individual with a backpack is not a threat.
[SPEAKER_02]: An individual with a range finder is not a threat.
[SPEAKER_01]: What about a man laying on a building that has direct line of sight of President Trump with a gun that people are screaming and pointing out?
[SPEAKER_01]: Is that a threat, Ms.
[SPEAKER_01]: Cheadle?
[SPEAKER_02]: Once that individual was identified, they were neutralized.
[SPEAKER_01]: No, they were neutralized.
[SPEAKER_01]: Crooks was neutralized after he shot President Trump in the face, Ms.
[SPEAKER_01]: Cheadle.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is he only a threat once he fires the weapon?
[SPEAKER_02]: As soon as the counter sniper identified that individual, they were able to neutralize them.
[SPEAKER_01]: How were people in the crowd?
[SPEAKER_01]: Okay, then let's just take it this way.
[SPEAKER_01]: People under your command did not consider him to be a threat, yet people in the crowd knew he had a gun and considered him to be a threat.
[SPEAKER_01]: That means that you are a complete failure as the director of the Secret Service, that people under your command don't perceive a man laying on a roof with direct line to the president with a gun.
[SPEAKER_01]: They don't perceive that to be a threat, yet the people in the crowd do.
[SPEAKER_01]: How is that possible?
[SPEAKER_00]: That's the last question, but please answer the question, Ms.
[SPEAKER_00]: Director.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'm not certain at this time how the information from the people in the crowd was relayed to any law enforcement personnel.
[SPEAKER_01]: No, you knew that everyone knew.
[SPEAKER_01]: The people there knew that there was a danger.
[SPEAKER_01]: They knew there was a threat to President Trump, and it was allowed to happen.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was there a stand-down order, Ms.
[SPEAKER_01]: Cheadle?
[SPEAKER_01]: Was there a conspiracy to kill President Trump?
[SPEAKER_02]: No. Absolutely not.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then how did this happen?
[SPEAKER_01]: And why are you still sitting here, not turning in your letter of resignation?
[SPEAKER_00]: Last question, but please answer and then I'll recognize Ms.
[SPEAKER_00]: Presley.
[SPEAKER_00]: Please [Speaker_02] do answer the question.
[SPEAKER_02]: That is what we are investigating to determine.
[SPEAKER_01]: We're waiting for your letter.
[SPEAKER_01]: We're waiting for your letter of resignation.
[SPEAKER_01]: And you really need to consider doing that before you leave today.
[SPEAKER_00]: Chair to recognize Ms.
[SPEAKER_00]: Presley from Massachusetts.
[SPEAKER_00]: Thank you.
->
[SPEAKER_00]: Chair now recognizes Miss Marjorie Taylor-Green from Georgia.
[SPEAKER_01]: Thank you, Mr. Chairman.
[SPEAKER_01][Demand for Specificity]: Miss Cheadle, I'd like to remind you that you're under oath.
[SPEAKER_01][Fact Presentation]: The site team has a senior supervisor, an advanced team, a protective intelligence team, a counter sniper element, and detail.
[SPEAKER_01][Demand for Specificity]: Who was the agent in charge?
[SPEAKER_01][Demand for Specificity]: How long has she been the agent in charge?
[SPEAKER_01][Demand for Specificity]: And what is her Secret Service background?
[SPEAKER_02][Stonewalling]: So I'm not going to provide a name.
[SPEAKER_01][Frustration]: Why not?
[SPEAKER_01][Accusation]: You're here to answer our questions for him.
[SPEAKER_02][Stonewalling]: I'm not going to provide names of you stated in your testimony.
[SPEAKER_01][Accusation]: You said I am here today to answer your questions.
[SPEAKER_02]: That is correct.
[SPEAKER_01][Demand for Specificity]: Answer the question.
[SPEAKER_02][Stonewalling]: I'm not going to provide names of our personnel.
[SPEAKER_01][Frustration]: Why not?
[SPEAKER_01][Appeal to Public Interest]: The American people are demanding these answers from you today, Ms. Cheadle.
[SPEAKER_02][Deflection]: I will do the best to provide you accurate information based on the facts that I have at this time.
[SPEAKER_01][Accusation]: You're not answering our questions.
[SPEAKER_01][Fact Presentation]: The advance element coordinates with other Intel or law enforcement partners, identifies threats and weaknesses at the sites and movements.
[SPEAKER_01][Demand for Specificity]: We'd like a copy of the advance report.
[SPEAKER_01][Demand for Specificity]: Have you brought it here with you today?
[SPEAKER_02][Deflection]: We will comply with the request for the documentation that has been requested.
[SPEAKER_01][Frustration][Accusation]: When will that be, Ms. Cheadle, because you should have brought it today.
[SPEAKER_02][Deflection]: I am certain that our personnel are working on obtaining all of that document.
[SPEAKER_01][Accusation]: I don't believe you, and neither do the people watching this hearing.
[SPEAKER_01][Accusation]: You're not doing well, as Mr. Moskowitz informed you.
[SPEAKER_01][Highlighting Non-Compliance][Implied Threat][Appeal to Public Interest]: You have been sitting here for over three hours and I have you know the entire country is demanding you resign and demanding that you be fired if you do not resign.
[SPEAKER_01][Accusation]: Things are not going well for you.
[SPEAKER_01][Demand for Specificity]: You need to answer the questions.
[SPEAKER_01][Demand for Specificity]: Was there a protective intelligence team and what technical resources were utilized for that event, specifically drone or helicopter assets?
[SPEAKER_02][Deflection]: There were a number of technical assets that were deployed for that event, and there was a protective intelligence team that was assigned to that event.
[SPEAKER_01][Accusation]: Why was Crooks able to fly a drone over the entire area the day of the rally and the day of his assassination attempt?
[SPEAKER_02][Deflection]: To my knowledge, he did not fly the drone over the entire area.
[SPEAKER_01][Demand for Specificity]: How did he fly a drone over the area, period?
[SPEAKER_01][Demand for Specificity]: Any part of the area?
[SPEAKER_02][Deflection]: Again, I would have to go back and check the timeline of when that took place and when the...
[SPEAKER_01][Accusation]: Why didn't you bring the timeline with you today to answer our questions?
[SPEAKER_02][Deflection]: I don't have all of the answers on the timelines based on the criminal investigation.
[SPEAKER_01][Accusation]: Were you not prepared today to answer our questions?
[SPEAKER_02][Deflection]: I am prepared to answer the questions based on the information and wanted to be able to provide...
[SPEAKER_01][Demand for Specificity]: Do you have a timeline that you... Do you have a timeline, at all, from any of the day?
[SPEAKER_02][Deflection]: I have a timeline that does not have specifics.
[SPEAKER_01][Sarcasm/Irony]: That's shocking.
[SPEAKER_01][Accusation]: That is absolutely unacceptable.
[SPEAKER_01][Accusation]: That means you are a failure at your job.
[SPEAKER_01][Fact Presentation]: Let's talk about things that are prohibited in Trump rallies.
[SPEAKER_01][Appeal to Authority]: And I've been to a lot of Trump rallies.
[SPEAKER_01][Fact Presentation]: Backpacks and bags.
[SPEAKER_01][Fact Presentation]: Bicycles.
[SPEAKER_01][Fact Presentation]: Firearms.
[SPEAKER_01][Fact Presentation]: any type of weapon or any other item determined to be a potential safety hazard, like a range finder would be one.
[SPEAKER_01][Fact Presentation]: At 5:10, Crooks is first observed by one of the snipers, ATR Sniper One, at the building.
[SPEAKER_01][Fact Presentation]: 5:10, President Trump was shot in the face at 6-11 p.m.
[SPEAKER_01][Fact Presentation]: 5:28, ATR Sniper One takes a picture of a bicycle in two bags.
[SPEAKER_01][Fact Presentation]: Those belong to Crooks.
[SPEAKER_01][Fact Presentation]: 5:32, AGR Sniper One spots Crooks looking at his phone and using a range finder.
[SPEAKER_01][Fact Presentation]: 5:55, Butler ESU Command confirms receipt of photos and states they have been relayed on.
[SPEAKER_01][Fact Presentation]: 6:05 PM, AGR Sniper One later communicates that Crooks is seen moving northeast in direction of Sheets and that Crooks has a backpack.
[SPEAKER_01][Fact Presentation][Accusation]: Two minutes before the shooting, while President Trump has been allowed to take the stage, people see Crooks laying on his stomach in a sniper position on the roof, and they're yelling he has a gun, and they are trying to alert law enforcement and Secret Service.
[SPEAKER_01][Demand for Specificity][Accusation]: Why was Crooks not shot by the snipers?
[SPEAKER_01][Demand for Specificity][Accusation]: Why was he allowed to be there?
[SPEAKER_02][Deflection]: As soon as the individual was identified as a threat, they were...
[SPEAKER_01][Interruption][Frustration]: No, no, no, no, no, no. What do you consider to be a threat?
[SPEAKER_01][Rhetorical Question]: A man with a gun laying in a sniper position?
[SPEAKER_01][Rhetorical Question]: A man that had a backpack?
[SPEAKER_01][Rhetorical Question]: A man that had a bicycle?
[SPEAKER_01][Rhetorical Question]: A man that had a range finder?
[SPEAKER_01][Demand for Specificity]: At what point is he determined a threat?
[SPEAKER_02][Deflection]: An individual with a backpack is not a threat.
[SPEAKER_02][Deflection]: An individual with a range finder is not a threat.
[SPEAKER_01][Rhetorical Question][Accusation]: What about a man laying on a building that has direct line of sight of President Trump with a gun that people are screaming and pointing out?
[SPEAKER_01][Demand for Specificity]: Is that a threat, Ms. Cheadle?
[SPEAKER_02][Deflection]: Once that individual was identified, they were neutralized.
[SPEAKER_01][Accusation]: No, they were neutralized.
[SPEAKER_01][Accusation]: Crooks was neutralized after he shot President Trump in the face, Ms. Cheadle.
[SPEAKER_01][Rhetorical Question][Sarcasm/Irony]: Is he only a threat once he fires the weapon?
[SPEAKER_02][Deflection]: As soon as the counter sniper identified that individual, they were able to neutralize them.
[SPEAKER_01][Interruption]: How were people in the crowd?
[SPEAKER_01][Interruption]: Okay, then let's just take it this way.
[SPEAKER_01][Accusation]: People under your command did not consider him to be a threat, yet people in the crowd knew he had a gun and considered him to be a threat.
[SPEAKER_01][Accusation][Appeal to Public Interest]: That means that you are a complete failure as the director of the Secret Service, that people under your command don't perceive a man laying on a roof with direct line to the president with a gun.
[SPEAKER_01][Accusation]: They don't perceive that to be a threat, yet the people in the crowd do.
[SPEAKER_01][Rhetorical Question]: How is that possible?
[SPEAKER_00]: That's the last question, but please answer the question, Ms. Director.
[SPEAKER_02][Deflection]: I'm not certain at this time how the information from the people in the crowd was relayed to any law enforcement personnel.
[SPEAKER_01][Accusation]: No, you knew that everyone knew.
[SPEAKER_01][Accusation]: The people there knew that there was a danger.
[SPEAKER_01][Accusation]: They knew there was a threat to President Trump, and it was allowed to happen.
[SPEAKER_01][Demand for Specificity]: Was there a stand-down order, Ms. Cheadle?
[SPEAKER_01][Accusation]: Was there a conspiracy to kill President Trump?
[SPEAKER_02][Stonewalling]: No. Absolutely not.
[SPEAKER_01][Demand for Specificity]: Then how did this happen?
[SPEAKER_01][Accusation][Implied Threat]: And why are you still sitting here, not turning in your letter of resignation?
[SPEAKER_00]: Last question, but please answer and then I'll recognize Ms. Presley. Please [Speaker_02] do answer the question.
[SPEAKER_02][Deflection]: That is what we are investigating to determine.
[SPEAKER_01][Demand for Specificity]: We're waiting for your letter.
[SPEAKER_01][Demand for Specificity]: We're waiting for your letter of resignation.
[SPEAKER_01][Implied Threat]: And you really need to consider doing that before you leave today.
[SPEAKER_00]: Chair to recognize Ms. Presley from Massachusetts. Thank you.