[SPEAKER_00]: Chair recognizes the gentleman from Arizona, Mr. Biggs.
[SPEAKER_01]: Thank you, Mr. Chairman.
[SPEAKER_01]: I request unanimous consent for that photo to go into the official record.
[SPEAKER_00]: Without objection to order.
[SPEAKER_01]: Thank you, Director.
[SPEAKER_01]: Your agency has a no-fail mission, and on Saturday, July 13th, your agency spectacularly failed.
[SPEAKER_01]: The failure resulted in the death of Corey Comperator and serious injury to two other rally attendees, David Dutch and James Koppenhaver, besides the injuries to President Trump.
[SPEAKER_01]: It is unfathomable that a 20-year-old on the radar of Secret Service and law enforcement before President Trump went on stage was able to climb onto the roof of a building with a rifle and fire off multiple rounds before he was neutralized.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was Mr. Crooks acting alone?
[SPEAKER_02]: Again, I would have to refer you to the FBI's investigation.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was he just a lone gunman?
[SPEAKER_02]: I would have to refer you to the FBI's investigation for motive.
[SPEAKER_01]: What did the technical services division determine was going to be the event perimeter?
[SPEAKER_02]: Those are questions that we are asking.
[SPEAKER_02]: And we are still.
[SPEAKER_01]: I mean, you're sitting here today.
[SPEAKER_01]: Come on, director.
[SPEAKER_01]: Everybody said this.
[SPEAKER_01]: You knew you were going to be asked that question because it's been asked multiple times.
[SPEAKER_01]: So this is an easy one.
[SPEAKER_01]: What did they determine was going to be the event perimeter?
[SPEAKER_01]: So you should know that.
[SPEAKER_01]: I mean, this is not, gee, I got to wait till someone else tells me.
[SPEAKER_01]: What was it?
[SPEAKER_02]: Again, I don't want to speak to specifics of the event or the place.
[SPEAKER_01]: This is a specific.
[SPEAKER_02]: I understand.
[SPEAKER_01]: This is a specific that you ought to know.
[SPEAKER_01]: As someone who said the buck stops with me, I'm going to stay in my job, I'm going to give the answers to the American people, and I know what happened, except for you're not going to tell us.
[SPEAKER_01]: And you're not going to tell the American people.
[SPEAKER_01]: And you yourself said in an interview that that foments ...
[SPEAKER_01]: this notion of conspiracy theories.
[SPEAKER_01]: Guess what?
[SPEAKER_01]: When you sit here and repeatedly tell people, 'Hey, I have to wait,' which has frustrated everybody on this committee, guess what?
[SPEAKER_01]: It undermines your credibility and whether you're really going to get to it.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I'm going to ask you again, what did the technical service division determine was going to be the event perimeter?
[SPEAKER_02]: We are still gathering reports.
[SPEAKER_02]: We are interviewing individuals.
[SPEAKER_01]: You know what it is though, no.
[SPEAKER_01]: You're just not gonna tell us, right?
[SPEAKER_02]: When I have those details, I will most certainly share those.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was the gun already on the roof or did the shooter carry the gun up with him?
[SPEAKER_02]: I do not have that information at this time.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, when was the last sweep of that roof done prior to the rally?
[SPEAKER_01]: So how many holds [a security measure where movement is restricted, often to secure an area before a protected individual arrives or moves] ...
[SPEAKER_01]: I mean, so most of us here have been in events and Secret Service has been there.
[SPEAKER_01]: There's been security.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I can't tell you how many times we've said there's going to be a security hold right here.
[SPEAKER_01]: So we're going to wait.
[SPEAKER_01]: and we wait ... to one or two or three things ... to [meaning: "for"] two or three minutes...
[SPEAKER_01]: And yet, we're hearing from you, apparently, that there were no holds in place, so ... ever instituted [at any point] here with President Trump's going on stage. [=that no security holds were ever instituted at any point during this event, even as President Trump was preparing to go on stage.]
[SPEAKER_01]: And you said, and this is, I think, connected with this, you said, they hadn't adjudicated the shooter to be a threat [=which I believe is connected to this other statement that you had said that they hadn't adjudicated the shooter to be a threat] *
[SPEAKER_01]: He was adjudicated to be a suspicious person, even though we've got some dynamic video that Mr. Krista Morthy put on the video for us.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I guess my question for you is, and I think you answered this, I just want to see if you're consistent with what you said about an hour and a half ago.
[SPEAKER_01]: What do you do if a suspicious person is identified by the agency?
[SPEAKER_02]: So at a number of our events, it is not unusual.
[SPEAKER_01]: I know it's not unusual.
[SPEAKER_01]: What do you do?
60A
[SPEAKER_02]: Those individuals that are identified as suspicious, we will send teams out to...
60B
[SPEAKER_01]: Was a team sent out here then?
[SPEAKER_02]: There were teams that were sent to identify and interview that individual.
[SPEAKER_01]: They were sent to interview the individual who's scampered up in camo on top of a roof within 130 yards of his target.
[SPEAKER_01]: And did your team get there?
[SPEAKER_01]: When did your team get there to conduct that interview?
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't have the details on the timeline.
[SPEAKER_02]: It is my understanding.
[SPEAKER_01]: So if you did send, if they did send a team, and they're going to interview them, and you said, you described that earlier as an investigation, why didn't they put a security hold on President Trump going on stage at that rally? **  [ =If a team was indeed sent to investigate this suspicious individual, as you've described earlier, why wasn't a security hold placed on President Trump to prevent him from going on stage at the rally while this potential threat was being assessed?]
[SPEAKER_02]: At a number of our protective sites, there are suspicious individuals that are identified all the time.
[SPEAKER_02]: It doesn't necessarily mean that they constitute a threat.
[SPEAKER_01]: Of course not.
[SPEAKER_01]: But here you got a guy scampering up the side of a building on top of a roof.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's identified to you, and you said you sent a team there, and you can't answer that.
[SPEAKER_01]: And this gets to one of my finer points, Mr. Chairman, if I can make it.
[SPEAKER_01]: And that is, we can have these kind of interview sessions, five minutes, you know, everybody gets a kiss at the pig, five minutes***, and she just gets [at these] stonewalls, not deliver[s] [the] answers.
[SPEAKER_01]: So we say, OK, we're going to put together a congressional committee, a blue ribbon committee.
[SPEAKER_01]: Same crap will happen.
[SPEAKER_01]: I am calling, and I'll support that, but I will tell you this, I am calling on the speaker to give us and put together a truly independent commission of qualified former Secret Service agencies, presidential and VIP protective services people who can actually conduct this kind of investigation and give us real answers, because I don't think you're gonna give us those answers.
[SPEAKER_01]: You should have come today ready to give us answers.
[SPEAKER_01]: I call upon you to resign today, today.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I also would say I've got a bunch of UC [Unanimous Consent] requests [used to enter documents into the record, extend speaking time, or handle other administrative matters quickly] if I can go ahead, Mr. Chairman.
[SPEAKER_00]: Proceed with the request.
[SPEAKER_01]: Thank you.
[SPEAKER_01]: I apologize.
[SPEAKER_01]: It might take a moment.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, Anthony Guglielmi, the Secret Service spokesman.
[SPEAKER_01]: One from him.
[SPEAKER_00]: Without objections ordered.
[SPEAKER_01]: Article U.S.
[SPEAKER_01]: Secret Service says it previously denied Trump requests for additional resources.
[SPEAKER_01]: New York Times reports.
[SPEAKER_01]: Without objections ordered.
[SPEAKER_01]: Secret Service says it denied earlier Trump requests for more federal resources.
[SPEAKER_01]: Without objections ordered...
[SPEAKER_01]: Secret Service acknowledges denying some past requests by Trump's campaign for tighter security.
[SPEAKER_03]: Without objections ordered.
[SPEAKER_01]: Preliminary findings by Senator Ron Johnson and his committee.
[SPEAKER_03]: Without objection to order.
[SPEAKER_01]: Article entitled "Notice anything different about Trump's secret service, detail"... , next...
[SPEAKER_01]: "Former Biden official corrects herself after saying Dems must turn their fire on Donald Trump to beat him" ...
[SPEAKER_01]: "Secret service director says Buck stops with her, but she will not resign."
[SPEAKER_01]: "Disney Star Wars Mark Hamill cracks joke about Trump's ear bandage following assassination attempt."
[SPEAKER_01]: "Biden - I haven't engaged in citing rhetoric.
[SPEAKER_01]: Trump has...
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm just talking about threat to democracy."
[SPEAKER_01]: A piece called "Who is Secret Service Chief Kimberly Cheadle."
[SPEAKER_01]: "[?garbled] says the God says Trump's solely responsible for violent rhetoric that led to attempt on his life."
[SPEAKER_01]: "Video actress Amanda Seals pushes conspiracy theory."
[SPEAKER_01]: "Donald Trump assassination trip was staged."
[SPEAKER_01]: Report "Secret Service identified rooftop as a potential vulnerability days before the rally."
[SPEAKER_01]: Watch "BlackRock removes ad showing former President Donald Trump's would-be assassin."
[SPEAKER_01]: "Why does the Biden administration have 100% confidence Secret Service after assassination attempt?"
[SPEAKER_01]: "Secret Service director, we didn't put snipers on the roof because it was kind of sloped."
[SPEAKER_01]: "Here's what Thomas Matthew Crooks did in the days leading up to Trump assassination attempt."
[SPEAKER_01]: Jacob Service, director under scrutiny for diversity initiatives after Trump assassination attempt.
[SPEAKER_01]: "The official story on Trump's shooting makes no sense at all."
[SPEAKER_01]: "Andrew McCabe says Trump assassination attempt..."
[SPEAKER_05]: Mr. Chairman, point of order.
[SPEAKER_05]: I'm happy to listen to all of them.
[SPEAKER_05]: Just so as to facilitate our proceedings.
[SPEAKER_01]: You don't want me to read?
[SPEAKER_01]: Is it too tedious?
[SPEAKER_05]: Well, we're not even really hearing them anyway, so if we could... It's up to you, Mr. Chairman.
[SPEAKER_01]: You would like me to slow it down.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was probably going too fast.
[SPEAKER_01]: "Secret Service's explanations for security failures ahead of Trump assassination attempt are not adding up."
[SPEAKER_01]: "U.S.
[SPEAKER_01]: reportedly received intel of Iranian plot to assassinate President Trump."
[SPEAKER_01]: What WTH Secret Service now saying that they didn't put any agents on the roof because slight slope was too dangerous.
[SPEAKER_01]: Report U.S.
[SPEAKER_01]: officials received intel of Iranian plot to assassinate Donald Trump before Crookes attempt.
[SPEAKER_01]: Exclusive GOP Rep Cloud.
[SPEAKER_01]: Homeland Security Agency is interfering in House's assassination investigation.
[SPEAKER_01]: White Trump's raised fist after surviving assassination attempt is triggering the liberal media.
[SPEAKER_01]: Questions swirl over the security lapse at Trump rally reviving old concerns about Secret Service.
[SPEAKER_01]: Secret Service scrambles to shift blame after Trump's shooting as backlash hits hard.
[SPEAKER_01]: Nobody contacted me.
[SPEAKER_01]: Must-see six-camera split screen of assassination attempt captures everything Shooter was in open two-plus minutes.
[SPEAKER_01]: Murillo, five reasons you should be angry.
[SPEAKER_01]: Breaking, Shooter spotted up to 30 minutes before firing, reported multiple times.
[SPEAKER_01]: pictures taken, no one stopped him.
[SPEAKER_01]: Cheadle calls the 30 minutes between noticing and neutralizing shooter a very short period of time.
[SPEAKER_01]: Secret Service Director says Buck stops with me on Trump's assassination attempt but won't resign.
[SPEAKER_00]: Mr. Biggs, we'll stop right there.
[SPEAKER_00]: We can retake them on the next one.
[SPEAKER_00]: I know there are more.
[SPEAKER_00]: But without objection, we'll enter into the record.
* AI and human:
Domain Blending:
The speaker is navigating between two distinct professional domains: legal proceedings (the hearing context) and security operations (the subject matter).
This results in a linguistic blend where terminology from one domain (legal) is applied to concepts from another (security), sometimes awkwardly.
Register Shifting:
There's a noticeable shift between the formal, legalistic register ("adjudicated") and the more operational, security-focused language ("security hold," "shooter").
This shift reflects the speaker's attempt to bridge the gap between the formal setting of the hearing and the practical, on-the-ground nature of the security incident being discussed.
Cognitive Dissonance:
The use of "adjudicated" in a security context creates a subtle cognitive dissonance. It implies a level of formal, judicial-like decision-making that may not accurately represent the rapid, dynamic nature of threat assessment in security operations.
Performative Aspect:
The choice of formal, legal-sounding language could be seen as performative – the speaker is not just asking questions but is performing their role as a government official in a high-stakes, public hearing.
Conceptual Metaphor:
There's an underlying conceptual metaphor at play: SECURITY ASSESSMENT IS A LEGAL PROCEEDING. This metaphor might be influencing the speaker's word choice, even if it doesn't perfectly fit the reality of security operations.
Interdisciplinary Communication Challenges:
This linguistic blend highlights the challenges of discussing specialized topics (like security operations) in a different specialized setting (a government hearing).
It demonstrates how professionals from different fields (politicians, legal experts, security professionals) might struggle to find a common linguistic ground.
Power Dynamics:
The use of legal terminology in a security context could be an attempt to assert authority or to frame the security failure in terms that imply a higher level of culpability or formal process.
This cross-talk between legal and security domains in the speaker's language is a rich area for analysis. It reflects the complex interplay between different professional languages, the challenges of interdisciplinary communication, and the influence of setting and role on language choice. It's a prime example of how language use in professional settings can be a delicate balancing act between precision, formality, and effective communication.
** Real-time processing: The speaker is formulating thoughts on the spot, leading to a less structured sentence. This is evident in the repetitive "if you did send, if they did send" phrase.
Cognitive overload: The speaker is trying to connect multiple ideas simultaneously - the sending of a team, the interview process, the earlier description as an investigation, and the lack of security hold. This leads to a jumbled sentence structure.
Self-correction and clarification: The shift from "if you did send" to "if they did send" suggests the speaker is trying to be more precise mid-sentence, but it results in redundancy.
Maintaining context: The speaker is attempting to reference previous statements ("you said, you described that earlier") while formulating a new question, leading to a complex sentence structure.
Emotional influence: The speaker's frustration or urgency might be affecting their ability to articulate clearly, resulting in a rush of ideas without proper organization.
Rhetorical strategy: The convoluted structure might be an unintentional result of trying to build up to the main point (why no security hold was placed) by first establishing all the preceding conditions.
Assumed shared knowledge: The speaker might be assuming that the listener can fill in some gaps based on previous discussion, leading to a less explicit statement.
Linguistic priming: The repeated use of "if" clauses might be a result of the speaker being primed by their own initial sentence structure.
***
Carnival Game Context:
In some carnivals or fairs, there's a game or event where participants are challenged to kiss a pig, often as a fundraiser or humorous spectacle.
This is typically seen as an unpleasant or embarrassing task that people do reluctantly or for show.
Metaphorical Application:
In the context of the hearing, the speaker is likening the five-minute questioning sessions to this carnival game.
Each participant (representative) gets their turn to "kiss the pig" (ask questions), but it's seen as more of a performance or obligation rather than a meaningful interaction.
Implications:
Superficiality: Like the carnival game, these questioning sessions are portrayed as more for show than substance.
Reluctance or Disgust: There's an implication that engaging in this process is unpleasant or distasteful.
Limited Impact: Just as kissing a pig at a carnival doesn't lead to any meaningful outcome, these brief questioning sessions are seen as ineffective in eliciting real answers.
Cultural Commentary:
By using this folksy, carnival-related metaphor, the speaker is also making a statement about the perceived circus-like or performative nature of these hearings.